BENJAMIN KERBY

3664 Cass St. Omaha, NE | bpkerby97@gmail.com | bkerby.qithub.io/bkerby | 402-739-1670

Summary

I am an Intern Developer with experience and interest in creating elegant frontends, utilizing modern technology. Over the course of one year I have assisted in updating 4 intranet applications, both frontend and backend with technology such as, Angular 6+, Spring Boot, and Web Components.

EDUCATION

University of Nebraska-Omaha

B.S. in Computer Science

Expected Graduation: May 2020

GPA: 3.66

Westside High School | Omaha, NE

Graduated May 2016

GPA: 3.71

WORK EXPERIENCE

Union Pacific Railroad

IT Intern | March 2018 - Present

- Pilot a new Web Components based Union Pacific Technology
- Attend/Participate in meetings about new/updated applications
- Write front end and back end code on a team using different technologies and languages

Universal Informational Services, Inc.

Digital Preservation/Assistant | Aug 2017 - March 2018

- Archive various media for preservation purposes
- Edit broadcast news clips, import historical newspaper PDFs
- Assisted with general office tasks, including office maintenance and organization

Aksarben Cinema

Usher/Box Office | Nov 2016 - Nov 2017

- Sold concessions and movie tickets, ushered theaters
- Cleaned concessions, theaters, and building

Brent Newman Lawn and Land

Landscaper | May 2015 - Aug 2015

• Built patios and water features to customer satisfactions

Sunset Hills Pool

Lifequard | May 2013 - Sept 2016

- Trained in CPR and Lifeguard classes
- Enforced safety rules to ensure pool members health and safety

SKILLS

- Languages:
 - Java, C++, JavaScript, TypeScript, SQL and Python
- Frameworks:
 - Angular 6+, Ionic 4+, Stencil, Spring Boot, and MyBatis
- Version Control:
 - Github, Gitlab, SVN
- Misc:
 - Microsoft Office Products, NPM, Google Firebase, REST Service Technology, Web Component Technology

RELEVANT COURSEWORK

- Managing Database Environments
- Data Structures
- Mathematical Foundations of Computer Science
- Digital Design
- Java 2
- Applied IT Innovation
- Introduction to Software Engineering

EXTRA-CURRICULARS

- Fraternity, Sigma Phi Epsilon
- Westside High School Varsity Swim Team | Team Captain
- Omaha Swim Club
- Latin Club

REFERENCES

Todd MurphyLaura PhamMichael PfieferCEOSenior Manager ITSenior Manager ITUniversal Informational ServicesUnion Pacific RailroadUnion Pacific Railroad402-342-3178402-544-7080402-544-0990

Please contact me with any questions.